Tyrelle Beltran

Valley Farm Road, Pickering, ON

289-388-2566 / tyrelle.beltran@gmail.com

I am a Help Desk/Service Desk/Technical Support Engineer with excellent Customer Service Skills. I am also a Software Engineering student aiming to acquire relevant Canadian work experience as well as becoming a valued contributor to your company.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Service Desk Engineer, TekConnect (Minneapolis, Minnesota) | October 2022 – December 2022

- Employed as a freelancer taking technical calls from a host of aged care providers based in the Chicago and Minnesota area such as Moments Hospice, Maple Hill Senior Living, Meadow Ridge Senior Living, Select Senior Living, Summit Hill Senior Living, and Health eMed.
- Able to communicate, assist and give technical support to caregivers, triage nurses, administrators, telehealth providers, and all other employees of the abovementioned facilities.
- Calls include:
 - Assistance with locating and tracking lost mobile phones via Samsung Knox (for Android) and Hexnode (for iOS).
 - Tablet and mobile phone setup for new hires. Setup includes installation of various software such as Point of Care, Home Care Home Base (HCHB), Point Click Care, Forcura, Eldermark, Zendesk, Microsoft O365, Azure, Outlook, etc.
 - Password resets and authentication setups (2-Factor Authentication or SMS).
 - Printer, Wi-Fi, Sound, or Bluetooth setup, and Docusign troubleshooting.
- Provided meaningful and emphatic assistance to clients.
- Creates knowledge base articles, user manuals, and other technical documentation which aids colleagues in getting step by step instructions on how to troubleshoot tasks.

Principal Help Desk Engineer, Deltek Systems (Makati, Philippines) | August 2013 – June 2022

- Provide quality support to Custom Care Analyst and Customers via telephone, email, and virtual sessions for Deltek Products, specifically Costpoint.
- Makes deep investigations into the most complex cases and develops or comes up with a workaround to assist clients who are not able to use the application feature.
- Focuses on high-priority cases for clients to ensure strong and timely resolutions for key issues.
- Works closely with developers to trace the root cause of defects and works to ensure long-term solutions are developed.
- Produces and maintains fixed scripts using SQL management studio/Query Analyzer for issues affecting multiple clients.
- Responsible for follow-ups and resolution of issues through coordination with Development and Quality Control teams.
- Read through existing Java codes to trace and possibly identify coding defects.
- Utilize MSS and Oracle queries to trace possible data errors causing data integrity defects. Compose SQL queries to further analyze data in clients' databases.
- Create virtual machines to mimic clients' environments to replicate client issues.
- Gather data logs to analyze errors and suggest next steps for Developers and/or Customer Care Analysts.

- Ensure that defects entered are documented clearly with easy-to-follow steps to replicate completely with attachments and screenshots if need be.
- Uses Team Foundation Server for defect management, Oracle RNT for customer issue management, and Microsoft Teams for cross-business collaboration.
- Escalates issues requiring development assistance to the Development team.
- Creates defects using Team Foundation Server and links information to Customer Care cases.
- Supports communication between Development and Customer Care, following up on requests for further information from either Development or Customer Care about specific escalated cases or defects.
- Reviews cases submitted to the Help Desk by Customer Care to determine if existing defects exist and create new defects as necessary.
- Generates ad hoc reports regarding cases assigned to the Help Desk team, those with development, those being worked on, etc.
- Attends Bug Fix Review meetings (IRB meeting) to provide additional information when required.

Sr. Technical Support Analyst, NetSuite (Makati, Philippines) | March 2012 – August 2013

- Provides excellent telephone and email support for various NetSuite clients.
- Coordinate with QA and Dev for the progress of defects and enhancements.
- Documents and files defects, bug reports and enhancements requests.
- Performs data migration to and from NetSuite.
- Assists clients in creating Custom Fields and Custom Forms in NetSuite with the use of HTML and SQL Function to source data.
- Constantly contributes to the Knowledge Base and continuously reviews existing entries to ensure that they are up to date.
- Liaise with the customer's Account Manager for clients' account concerns.
- Consistently ranked among the Top 10 Analysts with most cases resolved.

Application Support Analyst, Macquarie Financial (Makati, Philippines) June 2010 – March 2012

- Interprets, composes, and executes scripts using basic Oracle PL/SQL to further debug database issues as well as generate reports for various brokers and analysts for Australia and Canada.
- Served as the Shift Leader to support Macquarie Private Wealth Canada (MPWC).
- Represented Manila Central Operations in an Identity IQ Training in Sydney for 3 weeks. Training includes Risk Management and Health Check Operations.
- Supervises a team of 3 people in Sydney while constantly sending progress reports back to Manila.
- Liaise with Macquarie Private Wealth Canada (MPWC), Macquarie Advice and International (Sydney and New Zealand) for the resolution of bugs and other technical issues.
- Executes Morning Health Checks to test various Macquarie applications before market opens for New Zealand, Australia, and Canada.
- Trains Level 1 Analysts assigned in the evening operations in resolving MPWC issues as well as demonstrating case ownership, leadership, and excellent customer service.
- Part of a core team which conceptualized the migration from a 24x5 to 24x7 support.

Customer Technical Analyst, E*Trade Financial (Makati, Philippines) July 2007 – June 2010

- Communicates with various clients to aid with the installation of E*Trade's Equity Edge Software and Oracle, resolution of bugs and other technical issues.
- Conducts Database Analysis to further troubleshoot client's issue and escalate to Engineering if necessary.
- Interprets, composes, and executes scripts using basic Oracle PL/SQL to further debug database issues.
- Part of a pioneering team which implemented Salesforce.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Technology (Centennial College, Toronto) | January 2022 - December 2023

- Created a software documentation requirement for Glendora Gale (nursing facility based in Glendora, Los Angeles County in California). Interviewed a Certified Nursing Assistant regarding their technical requirements for the proposed automation and digitalization of patient records, room assignments, and social activities.
 - Skills and Methodologies used: Used Visual Paradigm to create UML-based diagrams: Activity Diagrams, Swimlanes, Use Case Diagrams, Context Flow Diagrams, Domain Class Diagrams, Entity Relational Diagrams, Sequence and State Diagrams, Architectural Context Diagrams, State Machine Diagrams and MVC Pattern Diagrams. Created Non-functional requirements and User Stories.
- Part of a team that created a survey website (similar to Survey Monkey) which lets a user create surveys, monitor the responses, and generate reports based on user response.
 - Skills and Methodologies used: Heroku, Visual Studio Code, GitHub, Node, Express, Javascript, CSS, and HTML.
- Currently developing software to match Animal Shelter rescued pets with potential pet owners to
 ensure long term bond between owners and pets. This software aims to decrease pet surrenders
 (owners deciding to return pets to animal shelters), minimize animal shelter operational costs, and
 create meaningful owner-pet relationships.
 - Skills and Methodologies used: Used Visual Paradigm to create Activity Diagrams, Swimlane, Use Case Diagrams, Low Fidelity Prototype Diagrams. Created User Stories (including story cards) and Non-Functional Requirements. Utilized MongoDB, Express, React, and Node architecture to create a full-stack web application.
- Involved in the creation of a business proposal involving a hypothetical CCTV Expansion Project for the requirement of CNET-307 (IT Project Management) course at Centennial College. Learned the principles behind the creation of a Business Proposal, Project Charter, High-Level Requirements, budgets, timelines, deliverables, and milestones.

Current GPA: 3.92